[{"answer": "I seen your hands. You been swinging a pick or a sledg", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 3, "question": " Get to what", "qsentId": 2}, {"answer": " Why don't you get to it, buddy", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 5, "question": "You know what I mean. You been givin' me a goin' over ever since I got in. Whyn't you go on and ask me where I been", "qsentId": 4}, {"answer": " Pa always said you was never cut out to be a preacher", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 7, "question": "Maybe you should a got yourself a wife", "qsentId": 6}, {"answer": "Ain't you seen your folks since then", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 9, "question": " It don't matter. Ever since I lost the sperit it looks like I just as soon go one way as the other.  I'll go your way", "qsentId": 8}, {"answer": "They're all gon", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 11, "question": "No. They wasn't people to write", "qsentId": 10}, {"answer": " my friend! Where's my folks, my friend", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 13, "question": " I know that! But", "qsentId": 12}, {"answer": "Gon", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 15, "question": "Ever'body got to get off. Ever'body leavin', goin' to that place. My folks, your folks, ever'body's folks.  Ever'body but me. I ain't gettin' off", "qsentId": 14}, {"answer": "For three dollars a day, that's what I'm doin' it for. I got two little kids. I got a wife and my wife's mother. Them people got to eat. my friend and on'y thing I got to think about is my own folks. What happens to other folks is their lookout", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 17, "question": " *Use", "qsentId": 16}, {"answer": "You think I'm touched", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 19, "question": "It don't matter. If I'm touched, I'm touched, and that's all there is to it", "qsentId": 18}, {"answer": "All you got to do is lay down an' watch", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 21, "question": " I don't think so. One come out here once an' I clipped him from behin' with a fence stake. They ain't bothered since", "qsentId": 20}, {"answer": "Heh'o my friend.  This is Connie, my husband", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 23, "question": " You do not see either", "qsentId": 22}, {"answer": " If my friend can scrabble along, I can do it too.  I smell spareribs. Somebody been eatin' spareribs? How come I ain't got some", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 25, "question": " Awright, but get me some a them spareribs, too. Get me a whole mess of 'em. I'm hongry", "qsentId": 24}, {"answer": "They use' to be a sayin", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 27, "question": " Sometimes. A little. Only it ain't scairt so much. It's just waitin' an' wonderin'. But when sump'n happens that I got to do sump'", "qsentId": 26}, {"answer": "Could you see your way clear to sell us a loaf of bread, ma'am", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 29, "question": "I know, ma'am... on'y it's for a ole lady, no teeth, gotta sof'n it with water so she can chew it, an' she's hongry", "qsentId": 28}, {"answer": "This ain't a groc'ry store. We got bread to make san'widges with", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 31, "question": "Whyn't you buy a san'wich? We got nice san'widges", "qsentId": 30}, {"answer": "I know, ma'am... on'y it's for a ole lady, no teeth, gotta sof'n it with water so she can chew it, an' she's hongry", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 33, "question": " I shore would like to do that, ma'am, but the fack is, we ain't got but a dime for it. It's all figgered out, I mea", "qsentId": 32}, {"answer": "Whyn't you buy a san'wich? We got nice san'widges", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 35, "question": "You can't get no loaf a bread for a dime. We only got fiftee", "qsentId": 34}, {"answer": " Give 'em the bread", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 37, "question": "Awright then, run out", "qsentId": 36}, {"answer": "Where you going", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 39, "question": "How long you plan to be in that place", "qsentId": 38}, {"answer": "How long you plan to be in that place", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 41, "question": "Got any plants", "qsentId": 40}, {"answer": "How's the swimmin'", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 43, "question": "Mind if we come in an' set", "qsentId": 42}, {"answer": "If we broke down maybe somebody'd give us a han'", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 45, "question": " It don't take no nerve to do somep'n when there ain't nothin' else you can do.", "qsentId": 44}, {"answer": "Seems like we wasn't never gonna do nothin' but move. I'm so tar'd", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 47, "question": " You ain'", "qsentId": 46}, {"answer": "Look, mister. We got a sick ol' lady. We got to get her to a doctor. We can't wait.  You can't make us wait", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 49, "question": "I swear we ain't got anything. I swear it. An' Granma's awful sick.  Look", "qsentId": 48}, {"answer": " Not her", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 51, "question": "I come out from that plac", "qsentId": 50}, {"answer": " You'll", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 53, "question": "Al ain't ", "qsentId": 52}, {"answer": "Morning", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 55, "question": "Mister, we're lookin' even under boards for work", "qsentId": 54}, {"answer": "Mister, we're lookin' even under boards for work", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 57, "question": "We can pick anything", "qsentId": 56}, {"answer": " Where you think you're going", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 59, "question": "Want to work, do you", "qsentId": 58}, {"answer": "You mean I can't even get outa here", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 61, "question": "I'll walk back", "qsentId": 60}, {"answer": "Take 'er on down, Al. I'll sign", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 63, "question": "You're tootin' we're gonna stay.", "qsentId": 62}, {"answer": " I'm ", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 65, "question": "I", "qsentId": 64}, {"answer": " I can't hardly believe it. Camp I was in once, they burned it ou", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 67, "question": "You got dances too", "qsentId": 66}, {"answer": "They don't get in here. Sometimes the boys patrol the fences, especially dance nights", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 69, "question": "We got the best dances in the county every Saturday night", "qsentId": 68}, {"answer": " I never knowed it! All I done was pull that string", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 71, "question": "Please don't", "qsentId": 70}, {"answer": "Lissen. You done busted it. You hear?  But lissen here. I won't tell nobody, y'understan'", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 73, "question": "I won'", "qsentId": 72}, {"answer": "Ma...  Ma, ", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 75, "question": " I can't he'p it, my friend. It don't make", "qsentId": 74}, {"answer": " You ain't to hurt them fellas", "docId": "Grapes-of-Wrath_-The.txt", "asentId": 77, "question": "Just don't use no stick nor no knife, no piece a arn. An' if you got to sock 'em, sock 'em where they won't bleed", "qsentId": 76}]